# **RISHI GUPTA | FRONTEND DEVELOPER**

+91-9958762171 | rishu.sic1608@gmail.com | New Delhi, India | in /meetrishigupta

# **PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY**

As a professional and freelance web designer & developer with front-end knowledge, I'm a detailed-oriented Frontend Developer with experience in HTML, CSS, Javascript, & JQuery . Highly adept at both independent at collaborative projects, I have been working on live projects for the past 4 years, gaining valuable experience and sharpening my skills in web development. With excellent concentration and communication skills, I am able to work effectively both as an individual and as part of a team.

	SKILLS		
	01/1120		
✓ HTML5	✓ React JS		
✓ CSS3 / SAAS	✓ Graphic Designing	Graphic Designing / Photoshop	
✓ Javascript ES6	✓ UX/ UI Tools (Fign	na, Adobe XD)	
DOM Manipulation	✓ Basic Knowledge of the state of the s	of Digital Marketing SEO	
Git (Github), Sandbox	CMS (WordPress,	WiX, E-Commerce)	

# PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

# **Adaan Digital Solutions**

Website Designer | (2019 - Present)

- Evaluate code(HTML, CSS, Javascript) to ensure that it is valid, properly structured, meets industry standards
- Excellence knowledge of Typography, Color Theory UI & UX, and responsive designs
- Design Prototypes of the website layout
- Collaborating with cross-functional teams: Web designers often work with developers, content creators, and other stakeholders to ensure that a website meets business objectives and user needs.

#### Letscms Pvt. Ltd.

Seo executive | (2018 - 2019)

Writing blogs, off and on-page SEO, designing social media posts, handling social media feeds, and reporting on Google Analytics, you have developed a range of skills that are highly valuable to any business. Your ability to create engaging and optimized content, as well as your proficiency in social media management and analytics, can help drive traffic to websites and increase brand awareness.

## **RELEVANT PROJECTS**

## Freelance Web Developer | 2019 - 2023

- Travel Website Using CMS and Design UI/UX
- Pharmaceutical Website Using CMS & HTML/ CSS and Design UI/UX

# **EDUCATION & COURSES**

- XII (CBSE 2017)
- Bachelor in Arts (School of Open Learning 2020)
- Master Diploma in Computer Engineering (IICS, 2020)
- Frontend Web Dev React (Coding Ninjas 2022)